Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Fated Hearts]
[قلوب مصيرية]
[Episode 14]
[الحلقة 14]
Is she an enemy?
هل هي عدو؟
She was.
لقد كانت.
And now?
و الآن؟
Whoever she is now is none of your business.
من هي الآن لا تعنيك.
Fine.
بخير.
[In Memory of Late Mother Qingyu]
[في ذكرى الأم الراحلة تشينغيو]
If your mother were still alive,
لو كانت والدتك لا تزال على قيد الحياة،
seeing you so troubled by love,
رؤيتك منزعجًا جدًا من الحب،
she would probably laugh at you.
ربما تضحك عليك.
Troubled by love?
هل تعاني من الحب؟
Before I avenge my mother,
قبل أن أنتقم لأمي،
[In Memory of Late Mother Qingyu]
[في ذكرى الأم الراحلة تشينغيو]
I have no time to think about such things.
ليس لدي وقت للتفكير في مثل هذه الأمور.
Why did you come to Yujing
لماذا أتيت إلى يوجينج؟
this time?
هذه المرة؟
How long will you stay?
كم من الوقت سوف تبقى؟
Is it for the wedding?
هل هو من أجل الزفاف؟
I'm not interested
أنا لست مهتم
in joining the fun.
في الانضمام إلى المرح.
I'm here to see a patient.
أنا هنا لرؤية المريض.
I'll leave after that.
سأغادر بعد ذلك.
[Wutong Mansion]
[قصر ووتونغ]
Make sure to send Lord Ling
تأكد من إرسال اللورد لينغ
back to Zhengnian Hall.
العودة إلى قاعة Zhengnian.
Yes.
نعم.
With me here,
معي هنا،
he's unlikely to die.
من غير المرجح أن يموت.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Xia Jingshi took Xiao Weiran away?
شيا جينغشي أخذ شياو ويران بعيدًا؟
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
[Wutong Mansion]
[قصر ووتونغ]
I locked him up in the patrol unit
لقد حبسته في وحدة الدوريات
precisely to make it easier for them to rescue him.
وذلك على وجه التحديد لتسهيل مهمة إنقاذه بالنسبة لهم.
If I'd kept him in my residence,
لو أبقيته في مسكني،
do you think Prime Minister Zhuang and his people
هل تعتقد أن رئيس الوزراء تشوانغ وشعبه
would've dared make a move?
هل تجرأ على القيام بهذه الخطوة؟
But Xia Jingshi
لكن شيا جينغشي
didn't go to get him himself.
لم أذهب للحصول عليه بنفسي.
He went through the envoys of the two nations.
لقد مر عبر مبعوثي البلدين.
At the Ministry of Rites,
في وزارة الطقوس،
they promised Xia Jingshi
لقد وعدوا شيا جينغشي
that they would help him bring Miss Yixiao back.
أنهم سيساعدونه في إعادة الآنسة ييشياو.
Xia Jingshi probably thought
ربما فكر شيا جينغشي
it wouldn't work out,
لن ينجح الأمر
so he gave the opportunity
فأعطى الفرصة
to Xiao Weiran.
إلى شياو ويران.
Which means
وهو ما يعني
Xia Jingshi has already tacitly acknowledged
وقد اعترفت شيا جينغشي ضمنيًا بالفعل
that Miss Yixiao
تلك الآنسة Yixiao
isn't your prisoner,
أليس سجينك؟
but stayed voluntarily.
لكنه بقي طوعا.
Xiao Weiran switched sides.
شياو ويران تحول إلى الجانب الآخر.
He saw the play couldn't go on,
لقد رأى أن المسرحية لا يمكن أن تستمر،
so he just dropped the act.
لذلك فقد توقف عن الفعل.
If you're right,
إذا كنت على حق،
Xiao Weiran
شياو ويران
probably won't return to Yujing.
ربما لن أعود إلى يوجينج.
Xia Jingshi will naturally reassign him elsewhere.
سوف يقوم شيا جينغشي بطبيعة الحال بإعادة تعيينه في مكان آخر.
If he stays in Susha,
إذا بقي في سوشا،
he would be under our close surveillance.
سيكون تحت مراقبتنا الدقيقة.
Where is she?
أين هي؟
Lu Ke?
متى؟
Didn't you send him
ألم ترسله؟
to chase Xun Xiang?
لمطاردة شون شيانغ؟
Oh, you mean Miss Yixiao.
أوه، هل تقصد الآنسة ييشياو؟
She's still at Zhengnian Hall.
إنها لا تزال في قاعة Zhengnian.
I helped her save Ning Fei,
لقد ساعدتها في إنقاذ نينغ فيي،
and she thinks one thank‑you
وهي تعتقد أن كلمة شكر واحدة
is enough to brush me off?
هل يكفي أن تتجاهلني؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
If it weren't for
لو لم يكن الأمر كذلك
your sake,
من أجلك
Lord Ling
اللورد لينغ
wouldn't care about that Ning Fei.
لا يهمني هذا يا نينغ فيي.
Miss Yixiao should at least offer
ينبغي على الآنسة ييشياو أن تقدم عرضًا على الأقل
to treat you to a meal.
لأدعوك لتناول وجبة طعام.
So rude.
وقح جداً.
Go tell the kitchen to prepare some good dishes
اذهب وأخبر المطبخ أن يعد بعض الأطباق الجيدة
and a few jars of fine wine.
وبعض جرار من النبيذ الجيد.
Call her over.
اتصل بها.
And invite Miss Ling
ودعوة الآنسة لينغ
and those kids too.
وهؤلاء الاطفال ايضا
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
you helped her,
لقد ساعدتها
and now you're inviting her to dinner?
والآن أنت تدعوها لتناول العشاء؟
Inviting her to dinner?
دعوتها لتناول العشاء؟
Don't I need to eat?
هل لا أحتاج إلى تناول الطعام؟
Don't you need to eat?
هل لا تحتاج إلى تناول الطعام؟
I've already eaten, Your Highness.
لقد أكلت بالفعل، سموكم.
Yixiao?
يشياو؟
She's not here.
إنها ليست هنا.
She sent Ning Fei off
لقد أرسلت نينغ فاي
and left just after dusk.
وغادرت بعد الغسق مباشرة.
Where did she go?
أين ذهبت؟
She didn't say.
لم تقل.
I thought she went back
اعتقدت أنها عادت
to the First Prince's residence.
إلى مقر إقامة الأمير الأول.
I knew you'd come.
لقد عرفت أنك ستأتي.
With your personality,
مع شخصيتك،
you'd have to get to the bottom of it no matter what.
سيتعين عليك الوصول إلى قاع الأمر مهما كان الأمر.
Aren't you going to tell me the truth?
ألا تريد أن تخبرني الحقيقة؟
On the cliff,
على الجرف،
were you that eager
هل كنت متشوقًا لهذه الدرجة؟
to see me dead?
أن تراني ميتا؟
I never once thought of
لم أفكر في ذلك مطلقا
killing you.
قتلك.
But since I was working with him,
ولكن بما أنني كنت أعمل معه،
I couldn't let you stand in my way.
لم أستطع أن أسمح لك بالوقوف في طريقي.
Meng Junran,
منغ جونران،
when will the military funds
متى سيتم صرف الأموال العسكرية؟
you promised arrive?
لقد وعدت بالوصول؟
Yesterday, 100,000 taels of silver
أمس 100000 تايل من الفضة
were already sent off under the escort
لقد تم إرسالهم بالفعل تحت الحراسة
of the Rongtong Escort Agency.
من وكالة رونغتونغ للمرافقة.
They'll soon reach Pingling City.
وسوف يصلون قريبا إلى مدينة بينجلينج.
I've fulfilled my promise to you.
لقد وفيت بوعدي لك.
But what about you?
ولكن ماذا عنك؟
Didn't you say that with our plan,
ألم تقل ذلك مع خطتنا؟
we would definitely win the Battle of Pingling?
هل سنفوز بالتأكيد في معركة بينجلنج؟
You don't need to tell me.
لا تحتاج إلى أن تخبرني.
I know it was that female commander of yours
أعلم أنها كانت قائدتك الأنثى
who ruined our plan with a single arrow.
الذي دمر خطتنا بسهم واحد.
Since that's the case,
وبما أن هذه هي الحالة،
Prince of Zhennan, why don't you execute her
أمير جينان، لماذا لا تقوم بإعدامها؟
to uphold military law?
لتطبيق القانون العسكري؟
What?
ماذا؟
You can't bear to do it?
لا تستطيع أن تتحمل القيام بذلك؟
One must pay the price for their mistakes.
يجب على الإنسان أن يدفع ثمن أخطائه.
How Yixiao should be punished
كيف ينبغي معاقبة ييشياو
is an internal matter for the Zhennan Army.
هي مسألة داخلية بالنسبة لجيش جينان.
It's none of your concern.
إنه لا يعنيك .
Who is that
من ذاك
masked man?
رجل ملثم؟
If you hadn't
لو لم تفعل
relentlessly tried to kill him that day,
حاولوا قتله بلا هوادة في ذلك اليوم،
would we
هل سنفعل
be in this mess today?
هل ستكون في هذه الفوضى اليوم؟
Yixiao!
ييشياو!
Stop!
قف!
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
don't try to stop me.
لا تحاول ايقافي.
That person from Susha definitely has ill intentions.
من المؤكد أن هذا الشخص من سوشا لديه نوايا سيئة.
He'll pass here
سوف يمر من هنا
on his way back to Susha.
في طريق عودته إلى سوشا.
Let me kill him.
دعني اقتله.
Yixiao. Yixiao, calm down!
ييشياو. ييشياو، اهدأ!
Your Highness, you don't want me to kill him?
سموك، ألا تريدني أن أقتله؟
Does that mean you want me dead?
هل هذا يعني أنك تريدني ميتا؟
What are you talking about?
ماذا تتحدث عنه؟
You know I wouldn't kill you.
أنت تعرف أنني لن أقتلك.
Why are you forcing me?
لماذا تجبرني؟
Don't be deceived by that person.
لا تنخدع بهذا الشخص .
We're running out of time.
لقد نفد وقتنا.
Just let me kill him.
فقط دعني اقتله.
No one deceived me.
لم يخدعني أحد.
This is all my own choice.
كل هذا هو اختياري الخاص.
Your own choice?
اختيارك الخاص؟
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
it's all right.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I know that you don't understand me now.
أعلم أنك لا تفهمني الآن.
You will understand in the future.
سوف تفهم في المستقبل.
Everything I've done
كل ما فعلته
is for our future.
من أجل مستقبلنا.
Give me the bow now
أعطني القوس الآن
and come back with me.
وتعود معي.
Okay?
تمام؟
Give me the bow!
أعطني القوس!
Whatever your reasons,
مهما كانت أسبابك،
you cannot sacrifice
لا يمكنك التضحية
the people of Zhennan Pass!
شعب ممر جينان!
War always costs lives!
الحرب دائما تكلف أرواحا!
I'm ordering you now
انا اطلب منك الان
to come back with me!
لتعود معي!
Soldiers spill blood
الجنود يسفكون الدماء
and die on the battlefield
ويموتون في ساحة المعركة
so the common people
لذلك عامة الناس
can live in peace
يمكن أن نعيش في سلام
and avoid slaughter!
وتجنب الذبح!
But for your own selfish reasons,
ولكن لأسبابك الأنانية،
you want to sacrifice the lives
تريد التضحية بالأرواح
of 300,000 civilians at Zhennan Pass!
من 300 ألف مدني في ممر جينان!
How could you be so cruel,
كيف يمكنك أن تكون قاسياً إلى هذه الدرجة؟
so heartless?
بلا قلب إلى هذه الدرجة؟
I am cruel?
أنا قاسي؟
Let me tell you,
دعني أخبرك،
if I had the slightest bit of
لو كان لدي أدنى قدر من
soft-heartedness,
رقة القلب،
I, Xia Jingshi,
أنا، شيا جينغشي،
wouldn't have lived to see this day.
لم أكن لأعيش لأرى هذا اليوم.
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
I'm begging you.
انا أتوسل إليك.
Just pretend nothing happened.
فقط تظاهر بأن شيئا لم يحدث.
Pretend you don't know anything.
تظاهر بأنك لا تعرف شيئا.
Go back with me!
عودي معي!
I won't go back!
لن أعود!
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I'm sorry I cannot obey your orders today.
أنا آسف لا أستطيع تنفيذ أوامرك اليوم.
If you insist on this path,
إذا كنت تصر على هذا المسار،
I'll kill him even if it costs me my life!
سأقتله حتى لو كلفني ذلك حياتي!
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
I knew this path
لقد عرفت هذا الطريق
would be full of obstacles,
ستكون مليئة بالعقبات،
but I never imagined
ولكنني لم اتخيل ذلك ابدًا
you'd become one of them.
ستصبح واحدا منهم.
I also never imagined
انا ايضا لم اتخيل ذلك ابدا
you could be so ruthless.
يمكنك أن تكون قاسياً جداً.
Fine.
بخير.
So you really want to do this,
إذن أنت تريد حقًا أن تفعل هذا،
right?
يمين؟
Didn't you just say
ألم تقل للتو
everything you had done
كل ما فعلته
is for our future?
هو لمستقبلنا؟
Then right now,
ثم الآن،
I'll act on behalf of my future self
سأتصرف نيابة عن نفسي في المستقبل
and stop you.
وأوقفك.
Will you let me?
هل تسمح لي؟
I have never begged you for anything.
لم أطلب منك أي شيء أبدًا.
Today,
اليوم،
I'm begging you.
انا أتوسل إليك.
No.
لا.
Yixiao!
ييشياو!
Put down the bow!
ضع القوس!
Don't force me!
لا تجبرني!
♪ The rain drifts endlessly ♪
♪ المطر ينهمر بلا نهاية ♪
♪ The old dream burns the heart ♪
♪ الحلم القديم يحرق القلب ♪
♪ Dreams sink into ruin ♪
♪ الأحلام تغرق في الخراب ♪
♪ Missing the warmth of your palm ♪
♪ أفتقد دفء راحة يدك ♪
♪ Awaiting dusk ♪
♪ في انتظار الغسق ♪
♪ Shadows take root in the mountain pass ♪
♪ الظلال تتجذر في ممر الجبل ♪
♪ In just a moment, tears stained ♪
♪ في لحظة واحدة، تلطخت الدموع ♪
♪ Amid the bustling sound of wind and rain ♪
♪ وسط صوت الرياح والأمطار الصاخبة ♪
♪ Who laughs at me, heart cold as the desert? ♪
♪ من يضحك عليّ، وقلبي بارد كالصحراء؟ ♪
♪ Dreams turn through a lifetime ♪
♪ الأحلام تتحول طوال العمر ♪
♪ Who sighs for me, enduring separations? ♪
♪ من يتنهد من أجلي، ويتحمل الانفصالات؟ ♪
♪ Love is a trial, harsh and cold ♪
♪الحب هو اختبار قاسي وبارد ♪
♪ Who crushes the lingering pain for me? ♪
♪ من يسحق الألم المتبقي بالنسبة لي؟ ♪
♪ Clouds vanish, rain ceases, seek me ♪
♪تختفي السحب، يتوقف المطر، ابحث عني ♪
♪ The world is vast and far ♪
♪ العالم واسع وبعيد ♪
♪ Time is unbearable to endure ♪
♪ الوقت لا يطاق ♪
At the Battle of Pingling,
في معركة بينجلينج،
your plan
خطتك
was to use the lives of hundreds of thousands
كان من المقرر أن يستخدم حياة مئات الآلاف
of civilians in the city as bait,
من المدنيين في المدينة كطعم،
wasn't it?
أليس كذلك؟
Once Feng Suige had breached Zhennan Pass,
بمجرد أن اخترق Feng Suige ممر Zhennan،
he would not only have died,
لم يكن ليموت فقط،
but would also have been branded with the stigma of a city massacre.
ولكنها كانت ستحمل أيضًا وصمة العار المتمثلة في مذبحة المدينة.
Of course he must die.
بالطبع يجب أن يموت.
Only his death
فقط موته
can throw Susha into utter chaos.
يمكن أن يرمي سوشا في حالة من الفوضى المطلقة.
Only with his death
فقط بموته
will I one day
هل سأفعل ذلك يوما ما
be free from fighting on two fronts.
أن تكون خاليًا من القتال على جبهتين.
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
you must understand that
يجب عليك أن تفهم ذلك
he is our real enemy.
إنه عدونا الحقيقي
Are the civilians in that city
هل المدنيون في تلك المدينة
your enemies too?
أعدائك أيضا؟
Yes.
نعم.
So many people can be sacrificed.
يمكن التضحية بالعديد من الناس.
I, Fu Yixiao,
أنا، فو ييشياو،
just a mere officer of the Zhennan Army—
مجرد ضابط في جيش جينان
what does it matter if I die?
ماذا يهم إذا مت؟
I never intended
لم اقصد ابدا
to kill you.
لقتلك.
If that day
إذا كان ذلك اليوم
I had truly wanted to kill you,
لقد أردت قتلك حقًا،
how would that arrow have ended up
كيف كان سينتهي هذا السهم؟
in your shoulder?
في كتفك؟
Well then,
حسنا إذن،
thank you for not killing me.
شكرا لك على عدم قتلي.
Xia Jingshi,
شيا جينغشي,
I'm asking you one last time—
أنا أسألك للمرة الأخيرة
who is
من هو
the masked man?
الرجل المقنع؟
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
can you
هل يمكنك
come back to me?
عُد إلي؟
I'm asking who that person is!
أنا أسأل من هو هذا الشخص!
Answer me!
يجيبني!
I don't expect you to understand me.
لا أتوقع منك أن تفهمني.
I only want to tell you
أريد فقط أن أخبرك
that I used to think
الذي كنت أعتقده
everything I wanted
كل ما أردته
was the most important,
كان الأهم
but after losing you, I realized
ولكن بعد أن فقدتك، أدركت
you were what mattered most.
لقد كنت ما هو الأهم.
I never truly wanted
لم ارغب في ذلك حقا
to kill you.
لقتلك.
Give me another chance.
أعطني فرصة أخرى.
You still refuse to tell me.
مازلت ترفض أن تخبرني.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
It was all my fault before.
لقد كان كل هذا خطئي من قبل.
Whatever happened before,
مهما حدث من قبل،
it was all my fault.
لقد كان كل هذا خطئي.
I did everything wrong.
لقد فعلت كل شيء خطأ.
I know that whatever I say now
أنا أعلم أن كل ما أقوله الآن
is useless.
لا فائدة منه.
All I ask
كل ما أطلبه
is for you to come back to me.
هو أن تعود إلي.
As long as you come back to me,
طالما عدت إلي،
I'll do anything you ask.
سأفعل أي شيء تطلبه.
I can give up everything.
أستطيع أن أتخلى عن كل شيء.
We can be like before.
يمكننا أن نكون كما كنا من قبل.
Let's start over.
دعونا نبدأ من جديد.
Let's be together again,
دعونا نكون معا مرة أخرى،
okay?
تمام؟
You look ridiculous now.
أنت تبدو سخيفًا الآن.
No matter what you say,
بغض النظر عما تقوله،
there's no going back.
لا يوجد عودة .
When you shot that arrow,
عندما أطلقت هذا السهم،
the old Fu Yixiao
فو Yixiao القديم
was dead.
كان ميتا.
You killed her yourself.
لقد قتلتها بنفسك.
You once saved me,
لقد انقذتني ذات مرة،
but you also killed me yourself.
لكنك قتلتني بنفسك أيضًا.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
our debts are settled.
لقد تمت تسوية ديوننا.
We owe each other nothing.
نحن لا ندين لبعضنا البعض بأي شيء.
Next time we meet,
في المرة القادمة التي نلتقي فيها،
we'll be enemies.
سوف نكون اعداء
Ning Fei is dead.
نينج فيي مات.
Tell Xiao Weiran about it.
أخبر شياو ويران عن هذا الأمر.
Think of it as closure.
فكر في الأمر باعتباره إغلاقًا.
I was careless.
لقد كنت مهملاً.
I never imagined
لم اتخيل ذلك ابدا
you'd choose this moment
لقد اخترت هذه اللحظة
to meet Xia Jingshi.
للقاء شيا جينغشي.
When did you get here?
متى وصلت هنا؟
Looks like
يبدو مثل
I can't escape
لا أستطيع الهروب
your grasp after all.
قبضتك بعد كل شيء.
What did he do to you?
ماذا فعل بك؟
Did you two fight?
هل تشاجرتم؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Answer me.
يجيبني.
What happened to you?
ما حدث لك؟
I'm really fine.
أنا بخير حقا.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll tell you
سأخبرك
what I need to tell you.
ما أريد أن أخبرك به.
I'm doing this for your own good.
أنا أفعل هذا من أجل مصلحتك.
Do you know what would have happened
هل تعلم ماذا كان سيحدث
if the Imperial Guards
إذا كان الحرس الإمبراطوري
had caught you just now?
لقد أمسكتك للتو؟
♪ Take down the setting sun as my heart ♪
♪أنزل غروب الشمس على قلبي ♪
♪ Fold the heaven and earth to make my wings ♪
♪ أطوي السماء والأرض لأصنع أجنحتي ♪
♪ If fate shows no mercy ♪
♪ إذا لم يظهر القدر أي رحمة ♪
You know what?
أتعلم؟
♪ Then don't blame my recklessness ♪
♪ إذن لا تلوموني على تهوركم ♪
I've made up my mind.
لقد اتخذت قراري.
Even if it means breaking off the marriage alliance,
حتى لو كان ذلك يعني قطع تحالف الزواج،
♪ I thought this life would drift like a solitary sail ♪
♪ اعتقدت أن هذه الحياة سوف تنجرف مثل شراع وحيد ♪
I'll rush in to save you.
سأسرع لإنقاذك.
♪ Yet I chanced upon you in the smoke-filled alleyway ♪
♪ ومع ذلك صادفتك في الزقاق المليء بالدخان ♪
[Wutong Mansion]
[قصر ووتونغ]
Did you have a nightmare?
هل كان لديك كابوس؟
You're all sweaty.
أنتم جميعا متعرقون.
I'll light the candles for you.
سأشعل لك الشموع.
No.
لا.
No need.
لا حاجة.
With the light,
مع الضوء،
all the monsters and demons
كل الوحوش والشياطين
will vanish.
سوف تختفي.
♪ Lost in the wilderness ♪
♪ ضائع في البرية ♪
♪ I've been looking for you ♪
♪ لقد كنت أبحث عنك ♪
♪ Even if devastation fills my eyes ♪
♪ حتى لو كان الدمار يملأ عيني ♪
♪ The shadows continue to sway ♪
♪ تستمر الظلال في التأرجح ♪
♪ The phoenix going against light ♪
♪ الفينيق يتحدى الضوء ♪
♪ Has been looking for a thousand miles ♪
♪ لقد كان يبحث عن ألف ميل ♪
♪ As years pass, dust stirs, stirring deep longing ♪
♪ مع مرور السنين، يتحرك الغبار، مما يثير الشوق العميق ♪
♪ All I ask is to be together forever ♪
♪ كل ما أطلبه هو أن نكون معًا إلى الأبد ♪
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
I was worried you'd have nightmares.
لقد كنت قلقة من أنك ستعاني من الكوابيس.
Aren't you going to ask me
هل ستسألني؟
what I dreamed about?
ماذا حلمت به؟
I can guess.
أستطيع التخمين.
Those dreams aren't scary at all.
هذه الأحلام ليست مخيفة على الإطلاق.
I couldn't see colors in them,
لم أستطع رؤية الألوان فيها،
so I knew they were just dreams.
لذلك عرفت أنها مجرد أحلام.
I remember...
انا أتذكر...
I had just left
لقد غادرت للتو
Xia Jingshi's.
شيا جينغشي.
You were probably just too tired.
ربما كنت متعبًا جدًا.
You fell asleep
لقد نمت
as soon as you left Xia Jingshi's.
بمجرد مغادرتك لـXia Jingshi.
I fell asleep?
غطت فى النوم؟
Yes.
نعم.
You really can sleep anywhere.
بإمكانك النوم في أي مكان حقًا.
You actually fell asleep on the street.
لقد نمت في الشارع فعلاً.
It really scared them at the time.
لقد كان الأمر مخيفًا جدًا بالنسبة لهم في ذلك الوقت.
But I told them not to worry.
ولكنني قلت لهم لا تقلقوا.
You must
يجب عليك أن
have been exhausted.
لقد تم استنفادها.
Exactly. Too tired.
بالضبط. متعب جدًا.
It's not dawn yet.
لم يأت الفجر بعد.
Go back to sleep.
عد إلى النوم.
I'll keep watch at the door.
سأبقى مراقبا عند الباب.
You can rest easy.
يمكنك الراحة بسهولة.
I'll keep
سأستمر
these candles burning.
هذه الشموع تحترق.
There's no need.
لا داعي لذلك.
I'm fine now.
أنا بخير الآن.
You should go rest too.
ينبغي عليك أن تذهب للراحة أيضاً.
Feng Suige,
فنغ سويج,
thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Who told you to provoke her?
من قال لك أن تستفزها؟
Those are just common methods
هذه مجرد طرق شائعة
to treat hysteria.
لعلاج الهستيريا.
She has a head injury
لديها إصابة في الرأس
and a blood clot in her brain.
وجلطة دموية في دماغها.
Any stimulus
أي حافز
or emotional outburst
أو انفجار عاطفي
could cause her clot
قد يسبب لها جلطة
to burst like a flood.
لتنفجر مثل الفيضان.
She's having nightmares
إنها تعاني من الكوابيس
because she was
لأنها كانت
overstimulated.
مفرط التحفيز.
If you want her
إذا كنت تريدها
to live peacefully,
للعيش بسلام،
stay away from all the chaos.
ابتعد عن كل الفوضى.
[Wutong Mansion]
[قصر ووتونغ]
Where are you taking me?
إلى أين تأخذني؟
What?
ماذا؟
You think I would harm you?
هل تعتقد أنني سأؤذيك؟
What are you up to?
ما آخر ما توصلت اليه؟
Whatever it is,
مهما كان الأمر،
it can't be anything bad.
لا يمكن أن يكون هناك أي شيء سيئ.
If you don't tell me,
إذا لم تخبرني
I won't go.
لن اذهب
[Wutong Mansion]
[قصر ووتونغ]
The wind picked up last night,
اشتدت الرياح الليلة الماضية،
and today the sky's full of dark clouds.
واليوم السماء مليئة بالغيوم الداكنة.
I'm worried it might rain
أنا قلق من احتمال هطول المطر
and ruin the herb fields,
وتدمير حقول الأعشاب،
so I want to check on them.
لذلك أريد التحقق منهم.
It's a long journey.
إنها رحلة طويلة.
I just want someone to talk to.
أريد فقط أن أتحدث مع شخص ما.
The dignified First Prince of Susha
الأمير الأول الموقر لسوشا
actually has the leisure
في الواقع لديه وقت فراغ
to farm?
للزراعة؟
What a coincidence.
يا لها من مصادفة!
I'd like to see it.
أريد أن أرى ذلك.
What are your plans now?
ما هي خططك الآن؟
Plans?
خطط؟
Since you left Xia Jingshi,
منذ أن غادرت شيا جينغشي،
you're no longer a female general of Jinxiu.
أنت لم تعد جنرالًا أنثى لجينكسيو.
And if I were to
وإذا كنت سأفعل
make you my concubine,
اجعلك محظيتي
it would seem far too frivolous.
يبدو الأمر تافهًا للغاية.
Have you ever thought about
هل فكرت يوما في
joining me?
الانضمام لي؟
Joining you?
الانضمام إليك؟
What's in it for me?
ما هو المستفيد بالنسبة لي؟
What's in it for you?
ما هو المكسب بالنسبة لك؟
You'll officially work for me.
ستعمل معي رسميًا.
Whatever happens from now on,
مهما حدث من الآن فصاعدا،
I'll protect you
سأحميك
and keep you safe.
ويحفظكم سالمين.
I know
أنا أعرف
you're trying to find out
أنت تحاول معرفة ذلك
what exactly Xia Jingshi
ما هو بالضبط شيا جينغشي
told me.
قال لي.
You can be straightforward.
يمكنك أن تكون صريحا.
There's no need to beat around the bush.
ليست هناك حاجة للمراوغة.
That day in the tent,
في ذلك اليوم في الخيمة،
the one meeting with Xia Jingshi
اللقاء الوحيد مع شيا جينغشي
was a masked man.
كان رجلاً ملثماً.
Xia Jingshi called him Meng Junran.
أطلق عليه Xia Jingshi اسم Meng Junran.
No matter how I pressed him,
بغض النظر عن كيفية الضغط عليه،
Xia Jingshi refused to reveal his identity.
رفض شيا جينغشي الكشف عن هويته.
In the Battle of Pingling,
في معركة بينجلنج،
their plan
خطتهم
was to lure you into the city,
كان يهدف إلى إغرائك بالدخول إلى المدينة،
use hundreds of thousands of civilians as shields,
استخدام مئات الآلاف من المدنيين كدروع،
and wipe out your Feng Battalion.
و محو كتيبة فنغ الخاصة بك.
Use civilians as shields?
استخدام المدنيين كدروع؟
If you had broken through Zhennan Pass
إذا كنت قد اخترقت ممر جينان
and entered Pingling City,
ودخل مدينة بينجلينج،
would you have slaughtered the civilians?
هل كنت ستذبح المدنيين؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
What if among the civilians
ماذا لو كان بين المدنيين
there were hidden crossbowmen
كان هناك رماة نشاب مختبئين
out to kill you?
هل يريد قتلك؟
When you can't tell the enemy
عندما لا تستطيع أن تخبر العدو
from the civilians,
من المدنيين،
what would you do?
ماذا ستفعل؟
I have to kill them all.
يجب علي أن أقتلهم جميعا.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
you'd become the true culprit behind the massacre
سوف تصبح الجاني الحقيقي وراء المذبحة
of hundreds of thousands in Pingling City.
من مئات الآلاف في مدينة بينجلينج.
Even if you managed to survive
حتى لو تمكنت من البقاء على قيد الحياة
and return to Susha,
والعودة إلى سوشا،
your reputation would be ruined.
سوف يتم تدمير سمعتك.
Everyone would see you
الجميع سوف يراك
as a bloodthirsty killer.
كقاتل متعطش للدماء.
What a clever scheme.
ما هذه الخطة الذكية!
It seems that
يبدو أن
if not for that arrow you shot at me that day,
إن لم يكن ذلك السهم الذي أطلقته علي ذلك اليوم،
I'd have died
لقد كنت سأموت
without a proper burial.
بدون دفن لائق.
I guess it was a blessing in disguise.
أعتقد أنها كانت نعمة مقنعة.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
thank you for the gold-threaded soft armor you gave me—
شكرا لك على الدرع الناعم المزين بالذهب الذي قدمته لي
it saved my life.
لقد أنقذ حياتي.
But why didn't you use it yourself?
ولكن لماذا لم تستخدمه بنفسك؟
With my martial skills, I didn't need to wear it.
مع مهاراتي القتالية، لم أكن بحاجة إلى ارتدائه.
I know what you're about to say.
أنا أعلم ما أنت على وشك قوله.
That I'm so arrogant,
أنني مغرور جدًا،
yet I still ended up defeated by you.
ولكنني انتهيت إلى الهزيمة منك.
I wasn't thinking that at all.
لم أفكر بذلك على الإطلاق.
You said it.
لقد قلتها.
A blessing in disguise, right?
نعمة مقنعة، أليس كذلك؟
Whose home is this?
من هذا البيت؟
Mine.
مِلكِي.
It's quite similar
إنه مشابه تماما
to my home in Zhennan Pass.
إلى منزلي في ممر جينان.
Looks like
يبدو مثل
you're not fond of living in a grand mansion either.
أنت أيضًا لا تحب العيش في قصر كبير.
That's my mother's hairpin.
هذا دبوس شعر أمي.
You mean
هل تقصد
the former empress of Susha?
الإمبراطورة السابقة لسوشا؟
This is my mother's private residence.
هذا هو محل الإقامة الخاص لوالدتي.
When she was young,
عندما كانت صغيرة،
she often led troops in battles.
كانت تقود القوات في المعارك في كثير من الأحيان.
Every time she returned from war
في كل مرة تعود من الحرب
and didn't want to go back to the palace,
ولم يرغب في العودة إلى القصر،
she would come here
انها سوف تأتي هنا
and stay for a while
والبقاء لفترة من الوقت
to escape all those constraints.
للهروب من كل تلك القيود.
I never imagined the former empress of Susha
لم أتخيل أبدًا أن الإمبراطورة السابقة لسوشا
was such a free-spirited woman.
كانت امرأة ذات روح حرة.
My mother always yearned
والدتي كانت تتوق دائما
for a life of freedom and ease.
من أجل حياة مليئة بالحرية والسهولة.
If it hadn't been for my father,
لو لم يكن والدي،
she would never have trapped herself
لم تكن لتحبس نفسها أبدًا
within the palace walls.
داخل جدران القصر.
So...
لذا...
you once lived here too?
هل عشت هنا أيضًا؟
When I was little,
عندما كنت صغيرا،
I often stayed here with my mother.
لقد بقيت هنا مع والدتي في كثير من الأحيان.
There were no palace rules here—
لم تكن هناك قواعد القصر هنا
just freedom and joy.
فقط الحرية والفرح.
She would spend her days with us
كانت تقضي أيامها معنا
planting herbs
زراعة الأعشاب
and tending flowers here.
والعناية بالزهور هنا.
Sometimes when my father came,
في بعض الأحيان عندما يأتي والدي،
he'd take me and Xiyang
سيأخذني أنا وشيانغ
to the stream to catch fish.
إلى النهر لصيد الأسماك.
Hug it.
عانقه.
Aside from
بصرف النظر عن
the four of us,
نحن الأربعة،
no one knew
لا أحد يعلم
what this place used to be.
ما كان هذا المكان في السابق.
Now, there's you.
الآن، أنت هنا.
♪ Love is a trial, harsh and cold ♪
♪الحب هو اختبار قاسي وبارد ♪
♪ Who crushes the lingering pain for me? ♪
♪ من يسحق الألم المتبقي بالنسبة لي؟ ♪
♪ Clouds vanish, rain ceases, seek me ♪
♪تختفي السحب، يتوقف المطر، ابحث عني ♪
♪ The world is vast and far ♪
♪ العالم واسع وبعيد ♪
♪ Time is unbearable to endure ♪
♪ الوقت لا يطاق ♪
♪ Lost in the wilderness ♪
♪ ضائع في البرية ♪
♪ I've been looking for you ♪
♪ لقد كنت أبحث عنك ♪
♪ Even if devastation fills my eyes ♪
♪ حتى لو كان الدمار يملأ عيني ♪
♪ The shadows continue to sway ♪
♪ تستمر الظلال في التأرجح ♪
♪ The phoenix going against light ♪
♪ الفينيق يتحدى الضوء ♪
♪ Has been looking for a thousand miles ♪
♪ لقد كان يبحث عن ألف ميل ♪
♪ As years pass, dust stirs, stirring deep longing ♪
♪ مع مرور السنين، يتحرك الغبار، مما يثير الشوق العميق ♪
♪ All I ask is to be together forever ♪
♪ كل ما أطلبه هو أن نكون معًا إلى الأبد ♪
Who's trying to catch you?
من يحاول الإمساك بك؟
Why do they want to kill you?
لماذا يريدون قتلك؟
You already know the answers
أنت تعرف الإجابات بالفعل
to these two questions.
على هذين السؤالين.
According to our previous agreement,
وفقًا لاتفاقنا السابق،
our cooperation
تعاوننا
ends here.
وينتهي هنا.
I said before
لقد قلت من قبل
that if you want to leave,
أنه إذا كنت تريد المغادرة،
I won't force you to stay.
لن أجبرك على البقاء.
You brought me here
لقد احضرتني هنا
just to tell me this?
فقط لتخبرني بهذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
But not exactly.
ولكن ليس بالضبط.
Then what is it?
ثم ما هو؟
Stop beating around the bush.
توقف عن الضرب حول الشجرة.
Just say it.
فقط قلها.
Whatever
أيا كان
Xia Jingshi's plan is,
خطة شيا جينغشي هي،
it only targets Susha
إنه يستهدف سوشا فقط
and me.
وأنا.
It has nothing to do with you.
ليس له علاقة بك .
If you're willing,
إذا كنت على استعداد،
I can find you
يمكنني أن أجدك
a place with beautiful scenery to live in.
مكان ذو مناظر طبيعية جميلة للعيش فيه.
You can take those children with you too.
يمكنك أن تأخذ هؤلاء الأطفال معك أيضًا.
So you don't want me to help you find
لذلك لا تريد مني أن أساعدك في العثور على
that masked man?
هذا الرجل المقنع؟
Even without you,
حتى بدونك،
I can find him on my own.
أستطيع أن أجده بنفسي.
Feng Suige,
فنغ سويج,
you seem
يبدو أنك
rather unfamiliar today.
غير مألوف إلى حد ما اليوم.
Your sudden concern for me
اهتمامك المفاجئ بي
makes me a bit scared.
يجعلني خائفا قليلا.
What are you up to?
ما آخر ما توصلت اليه؟
What purpose can I have?
ما هو الهدف الذي يمكن أن أحققه؟
Whatever your purpose,
مهما كان هدفك،
you clearly don't have good intentions.
من الواضح أنك لا تملك نوايا حسنة.
Feng Suige,
فنغ سويج,
since the day
منذ اليوم
you arrested me,
لقد اعتقلتني
I've wanted to tell you
لقد أردت أن أخبرك
that even though you hold every advantage
أنه على الرغم من أنك تمتلك كل المزايا
and seem certain to win,
ويبدو من المؤكد الفوز،
you will never
لن تفعل ذلك ابدا
beat me.
اضربني.
Why?
لماذا؟
Because I always know
لأني أعرف دائما
what you're thinking.
ما الذي تفكر فيه.
There's quite a big fish here.
هناك سمكة كبيرة جدًا هنا.
♪ Take down the setting sun as my heart ♪
♪أنزل غروب الشمس على قلبي ♪
♪ Fold the heaven and earth to make my wings ♪
♪ أطوي السماء والأرض لأصنع أجنحتي ♪
♪ If fate shows no mercy ♪
♪ إذا لم يظهر القدر أي رحمة ♪
♪ Then don't blame my recklessness ♪
♪ إذن لا تلوموني على تهوركم ♪
♪ I thought this life would drift like a solitary sail ♪
♪ اعتقدت أن هذه الحياة سوف تنجرف مثل شراع وحيد ♪
♪ Yet I chanced upon you in the smoke-filled alleyway ♪
♪ ومع ذلك صادفتك في الزقاق المليء بالدخان ♪
♪ Like a fleeting flower falling into ♪
♪ مثل زهرة عابرة تسقط في ♪
She's having nightmares
إنها تعاني من الكوابيس
because she was
لأنها كانت
overstimulated.
مفرط التحفيز.
♪ My eyes ♪
♪ عيني ♪
If you want her
إذا كنت تريدها
to live peacefully,
للعيش بسلام،
stay away from all the chaos.
ابتعد عن كل الفوضى.
♪ Once I was like a frost-edged sword ♪
♪ ذات مرة كنت مثل سيف ذو حدين من الصقيع ♪
♪ Sweeping across the battlefield in gleaming light ♪
♪ اكتساح ساحة المعركة في ضوء ساطع ♪
♪ Never thought who'd lay me to rest ♪
♪ لم أفكر أبدًا من الذي سيدفنني ♪
♪ Once unstoppable and sharp ♪
♪ كان ذات يوم لا يمكن إيقافه وكان حادًا ♪
♪ Now my heart's tied to you ♪
♪ الآن قلبي مرتبط بك ♪
♪ Thinking of you day and night ♪
♪ أفكر فيك ليلًا ونهارًا ♪
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
We found Xun Xiang.
لقد وجدنا شون شيانغ.
Lu Ke is watching him.
لو كي يراقبه.
I see.
أرى.
When she wakes,
عندما تستيقظ
escort her back to the residence.
رافقها إلى مقر إقامتها.
Be extremely careful.
كن حذرا للغاية.
Yes.
نعم.
When you planned to kill,
عندما خططت للقتل،
did you ever think about your daughter?
هل فكرت يوما في ابنتك؟
Do you plan to surrender,
هل تخطط للاستسلام؟
or should I have your whole family arrested
أو هل يجب أن أعتقل عائلتك بأكملها؟
to keep you company?
لأبقيك في صحبتي؟
Get in!
أدخل!
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
the Xun family is distantly related to the Empress.
ترتبط عائلة شون بالإمبراطورة عن بعد.
Aren't we being
ألسنا كذلك؟
a bit too conspicuous?
واضح قليلا؟
Fu Yixiao is under my protection.
فو Yixiao تحت حمايتي.
I want everyone in Yujing City
أريد الجميع في مدينة يوجينج
to know about this.
لمعرفة هذا.
Whoever dares to harm her,
من تجرأ على إيذائها،
I will kill them.
سأقتلهم
Your Majesty, I came
جلالتك لقد جئت
to report something important.
للإبلاغ عن شيء مهم.
Recently, someone actually
في الآونة الأخيرة، شخص ما في الواقع
attempted to assassinate a member of my household.
حاول اغتيال أحد أفراد أسرتي.
We've caught the culprit.
لقد ألقينا القبض على الجاني.
He's outside the hall.
إنه خارج القاعة.
Are the Ministry of Justice
هل وزارة العدل
and the Court of Judicial Review both closed?
ومحكمة المراجعة القضائية مغلقة؟
If someone tries to assassinate you,
إذا حاول أحدهم اغتيالك،
just go to them.
فقط اذهب إليهم.
What do you mean by bringing the assassin
ماذا تقصد بإحضار القاتل؟
into the palace?
إلى القصر؟
It's because this person has a special identity.
لأن هذا الشخص لديه هوية خاصة.
I have no authority to handle him.
ليس لدي السلطة للتعامل معه.
I request Your Majesty's judgment.
أطلب حكم جلالتكم.
Lu Ke.
لو كي.
Kneel!
اركع!
Your Majesty, spare me!
يا صاحب الجلالة، أنقذني!
Is this the child from the Xun family?
هل هذا هو الطفل من عائلة شون؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Majesty, you remember
جلالتك، هل تتذكر؟
the Empress's relatives
أقارب الإمبراطورة
very well.
جيد جدا.
Are you saying
هل انت تقول
that this person's assassination attempt at your residence
أن محاولة اغتيال هذا الشخص في مقر إقامتك
is connected to the Empress?
هل هو متصل بالإمبراطورة؟
Your Majesty, you are wise.
جلالتك أنت حكيم.
The truth and justice
الحقيقة والعدالة
rest entirely on your judgment.
يعتمد كليا على حكمك.
I'm afraid the Empress already knows
أخشى أن الإمبراطورة تعرف بالفعل
that I brought Xun Xiang
أنني أحضرت شون شيانغ
into the palace.
إلى القصر.
As for how deeply
أما بالنسبة لمدى العمق
she is involved,
إنها متورطة
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
please wait and see.
يرجى الانتظار والرؤية.
You seem quite confident.
يبدو أنك واثق جدًا.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحياتي جلالتك.
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
First Prince,
الأمير الأول
you brought someone covered in blood
لقد أحضرت شخصًا مغطى بالدماء
before His Majesty.
أمام جلالته.
If it startled His Majesty,
إذا فاجأ جلالته،
what punishment would befit you?
ما هو العقاب الذي يليق بك؟
His Majesty is a warrior emperor
جلالته هو إمبراطور محارب
who has expanded our territories
من وسع أراضينا
and achieved unparalleled merit.
وحققت فضلًا لا مثيل له.
He will not be startled so easily.
لن يفاجأ بسهولة.
Empress,
الإمبراطورة
why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
I heard today that
سمعت اليوم أن
the First Prince entered the palace unexpectedly
دخل الأمير الأول القصر بشكل غير متوقع
and feared he might displease you again.
وخاف أن يغضبك مرة أخرى.
His Majesty didn't sleep well last night
جلالته لم ينم جيدا الليلة الماضية
and woke up dizzy this morning.
واستيقظت وأنا أشعر بالدوار هذا الصباح.
First Prince,
الأمير الأول
please speak to His Majesty patiently.
يرجى التحدث مع جلالته بصبر.
Don't upset him.
لا تزعجه.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
I truly admire
أنا معجب حقا
your concern for His Majesty.
اهتمامكم بجلالته.
However,
لكن،
you may not know,
ربما لا تعرف،
but General Xun
لكن الجنرال شون
has already confessed everything.
وقد اعترف بكل شيء بالفعل.
I don't understand
لا أفهم
what First Prince is saying.
ماذا يقول الأمير الأول؟
But if I weren't here today,
ولكن لو لم أكن هنا اليوم،
some matters
بعض الأمور
might have been impossible to clarify.
ربما كان من المستحيل توضيح ذلك.
Our Zhuang family and the Xun family are only distant relatives,
عائلتنا تشوانغ وعائلة شون هم مجرد أقارب بعيدين،
with very little connection.
مع اتصال قليل جدًا.
I don't know
لا أعرف
how Xun Xiang offended
كيف أساء شون شيانغ
the First Prince today.
الأمير الأول اليوم.
But no matter what the Xun family has done,
ولكن بغض النظر عما فعلته عائلة شون ،
I am unaware.
أنا لا أعلم.
How this matter should be handled
كيف يجب التعامل مع هذه المسألة
is for Your Majesty to decide.
هذا الأمر متروك لجلالتك لتقرره.
Although I'm not welcomed in Yujing,
على الرغم من أنني غير مرحب بي في يوجينج،
everything should follow the principle
كل شيء يجب أن يتبع المبدأ
of fair rewards and punishments.
من المكافآت والعقوبات العادلة.
Otherwise, how can I continue
وإلا فكيف يمكنني الاستمرار؟
living here?
تعيش هنا؟
First Prince,
الأمير الأول
when has His Majesty ever let you
متى سمح لك جلالته؟
suffer any injustice?
هل تعاني من أي ظلم؟
-Isn't this... -Empress.
-أليس هذا... -الإمبراطورة.
This is not the harem.
هذا ليس الحريم.
I'll talk to you
سأتحدث معك
when I get back.
عندما أعود.
You may leave now.
يمكنك المغادرة الآن.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم جلالتك.
I know you suspect the Empress
أعلم أنك تشك في الإمبراطورة
of involvement,
من المشاركة،
but you have no solid evidence.
ولكن ليس لديك دليل قاطع.
Didn't he say nothing at all?
ولم يقل شيئا على الإطلاق؟
Does it matter
هل يهم؟
whether he did or not?
هل فعل ذلك أم لا؟
I am truly innocent...
أنا بريء حقا...
Xiyang is about to be married.
شيانغ على وشك الزواج.
This is the biggest matter right now.
هذه هي المسألة الأكبر في الوقت الراهن.
You have been close to her since childhood.
لقد كنت قريبًا منها منذ الطفولة.
Before her wedding,
قبل زفافها،
you cannot let the Jinxiu people
لا يمكنك السماح لشعب جينكسيو
see our royal family as divided.
أرى أن عائلتنا المالكة منقسمة.
Your Majesty, since you said you will not pursue it,
يا صاحب الجلالة، بما أنك قلت أنك لن تسعى إلى ذلك،
then we will not.
إذن لن نفعل ذلك.
But in the future,
ولكن في المستقبل،
if I act against anyone around the Empress,
إذا قمت بالتصرف ضد أي شخص حول الإمبراطورة،
I ask that you treat it the same way.
أطلب منك أن تعامله بنفس الطريقة.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
She is your mother after all!
إنها أمك بعد كل شيء!
She has never been my mother.
لم تكن أمي أبدًا.
For the sake of a mere Jinxiu prisoner of war,
من أجل مجرد أسير حرب جينكسيو،
you're deliberately
أنت عمدا
opposing me today.
يعارضني اليوم.
No matter how lawless you are,
بغض النظر عن مدى عدم التزامك بالقانون،
there are limits.
هناك حدود.
After all, Susha
بعد كل شيء، سوشا
is still ruled by me.
لا يزال يحكمني.
Of course you're the ruler.
بالطبع أنت الحاكم.
Wasn't it also you back then
ألم تكن أنت أيضًا في ذلك الوقت؟
who tacitly allowed them
الذين سمحوا لهم ضمنا
to murder my mother?
لقتل أمي؟
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Please don't be angry.
من فضلك لا تغضب.
-Your health is more important. -Your Highness.
-صحتك أهم. -سموكم.
Your Highness, kneel, please.
صاحب السمو، اركع من فضلك.
I'm begging you,
انا أتوسل إليك
please kneel now!
من فضلك اركع الآن!
I issued a strict order long ago
لقد أصدرت أمراً صارماً منذ زمن طويل
forbidding anyone
منع أي شخص
from mentioning the late Empress.
من ذكر الإمبراطورة الراحلة.
How dare you defy my decree?
كيف تجرؤ على تحدي مرسومي؟
Why forbid it?
لماذا يمنع ذلك؟
Could it be that you feel guilty?
هل من الممكن أن تشعر بالذنب؟
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Do you really want me to repeat it?
هل تريدني حقا أن أكررها؟
Convey my imperial order:
نقل أمري الإمبراطوري:
The First Prince has committed great insubordination
لقد ارتكب الأمير الأول عصيانًا كبيرًا
and defied his elders.
وتحدى شيوخه.
He is to return to his residence and reflect on his conduct.
وعليه أن يعود إلى منزله ويتأمل في سلوكه.
Before Xiyang's wedding, the ancestral offering ceremony
قبل زفاف شيانغ، أقيم حفل تقديم القرابين للأجداد
will be performed instead by the Second Prince, Chengyang.
سيتم تنفيذه بدلا من ذلك من قبل الأمير الثاني، تشنغ يانغ.
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
I shall take my leave as well.
سوف آخذ إجازتي أيضاً.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.